He went to bed an all-American kid and woke up the son of Russian spies.
Little Nikita is a drama, action, thriller film directed by Richard Benjamin.
An FBI agent works to uncover an all-American family as Soviet sleeper agents,
and gets caught up in friendship with their oblivious teenage son.
Roy Parmenter, played by Sidney Poitier.
Jeff Grant, played by River Phoenix.
Richard Grant, played by Richard Jenkins.
Elizabeth Grant, played by Caroline Kava.
Barbara Kerry, played by Lucy Deakins.
Konstantin Karpov, played by Richard Bradford.
Little Nikita is a 1988 American thriller film directed by Richard
Benjamin and starring River Phoenix and Sidney Poitier.
The film marks the first collaboration between Phoenix and
Poitier (the second being Sneakers in 1992).
The film explores themes of spy, fbi, teenage boy,
pursuit in traffic, soviet spy.
The tone is emotional and intense.